Dan Nguyen

Melbourne, Australia daan.nguyen@gmail.com http://daan-nguyen.github.io 0402 830 449

APR 2014 - Current

Software Engineer

Adaptable, motivated and personable software engineer with 8 years of experience over a range of technologies and platforms focusing on web applications & content management systems.

Genuinely passionate about technology with a keen eye for detail and a strong personal interest in design, typography, user experience and always keen to learn more. Seeking an opportunity to further grow my front-end capability and join a team of like-minded individuals to help solve challenging problems and deliver beautifully coded, quality frontends and applications that I can be proud of.

Experience

In-depth experience across the full development stack from backend development in Java and C# to front-end development dealing asynchronous Javascript applications, responsive design and cross-browser compatibility. Strong breadth of knowledge and experience with Agile practices, OOP, design patterns, development practices such as version control & continuous integration.

Client Solutions Team, IE Agency, Developer

- Assisted Telstra Digital to establish various development processes and best practice, including; git branching, merging and release strategies, peer code reviews and coding quality standards for frontend development.
- Developed and designed responsive, reusable AEM UI components and page templates for Telstra.com.au AEM (5.6.1) platform migration project. Includes creation of frontend Grunt build to streamline development and integration with backend development in Sydney and offshore.
- Managed development tasks for frontend development onshore and offshore and conducted code reviews and release governance to ensure quality as part of AEM platform migration.
- SME support for project planning, working with stakeholders, producers and UI/UX designers to provide development guidance, feasibility determination and estimations.
- Frontend and backend (Java) development for day to day operations of Telstra.com.au, supporting content production staff to launch new components and features as part of product launches and sales objectives.
- Team Coordinator at Telstra Digital for IE Agency's Client Solutions development team members. Provided on boarding and training of new IE development staff at Telstra Digital and conducted interviews for new team members.

MAY 2012 - APR 2014

Application Development & Testing, NAB, Web Developer

- Established NAB UI—an internal framework based on Bootstrap—as the first step to improve the presentation, usability, compatibility and consistency of internal web application front-ends whilst reducing development effort, costs and the reliance on a specific browser environment as internal applications are made available to devices beyond the desktop.
- Designed and developed user experience and front-end for internal Relationships & Services application, translating the application from a DOS based front-end to a Java Spring MVC web application that improved usability & accessibility for up to 10,000 front line staff. Test-driven development with full suite of Selenium functional tests integrated into Jenkins CI process.
- Seconded to Mobile & Emerging Technology to develop an administration application built on AngularJS consuming internal REST APIs for NAB Flik (mobile consumer to consumer payments platform).
- Lead front-end development for nabbroker.com.au based on agency design. Delivered cross-browser, responsive front-end consisting of HTML/CSS & C# .NET custom user controls integrated into templates for OpenText Red Dot CMS. Build completed within 6 week deadline leveraging agile methodologies.
- Experience working with small (4-8) and large (15-25) teams utilising agile practices and methodologies.

APR 2011 - MAY 2012

Business Intelligence Solutions Centre, NAB, BI Developer

- Worked on pilot project introducing Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise into the organisation, developing standards and processes for use of OBIEE within BISC.
- Developed self-service universes & automated reporting for business stakeholders using Business Objects Webi analytics tools.

FEB 2007 - APR 2011

Web Applications - Intranet Portal, NAB, Graduate/Analyst Programmer

- Lead development of J2EE Business Objects Viewer web application to implement upgrades required to integrate with Business Objects XI Release 3.
- Implementation of new visual design as part of enterprise intranet refresh.
- Designed & developed J2EE intranet video delivery portlet & sub-site to replace terrestrial television delivery of NABtv, leveraged existing file delivery infrastructure to minimise network impact.
- Responsible for development and support of enterprise intranet based on IBM WebSphere Portal, IBM Web Content Manager, Autonomy Search, Confluence Wiki and other J2EE web applications including Business Objects report viewer serving ~5,000 unique reports to thousands of front line and back office staff.

Education

2002 - 2006 1998 - 2001 BEng (Hons) in Software, BCom in Accounting, University of Melbourne Victorian Certificate of Education, TER of 98.70, Melbourne High School

Skills Summary

Server-side Java, C#/ASP.NET

Front-end HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS, BackboneJS

Bootstrap, Foundation, SASS/SCSS, Less, Grunt

Version Control Git, TFS, Clearcase

Other Tools Selenium, JUnit, NUnit, Jenkins CI, JIRA, HP QC/ALM, Photoshop,

Eclipse, Visual Studio 2010

Storage Oracle, IBM DB2, MS-SQL

Non-commercial C, Objective-C, PHP, MySQL, nodeJS

References

References available upon request.